ANDREW PEDERSEN

SOFTWARF FNGINFFR

■ W.ANDREW.PEDERSEN@GMAIL.COM \$\ 970-531-9665 \$\ DENVER, CO

in Wandrewpedersen O andimalfresh

SUMMARY

I have been enamored with computers and the science behind them since I the age of six. Being involved with the webdev communities like Phora/Pod Collective and the Unigine hardware enthusiast community since the late 90's for many years I have always sought out a career in technology. This helped fuel my passion to be constantly challenged and learning now moving forward in my career as a Software Engineer/Full Stack Web Developer.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Java

TOOLS: React, Express.js, Node.js, Git/Github, Firebase, Heroku, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Premier, Linux, Joomla, Wordpress, Knex, PostgreSOL, VUE, React-Native, NodeMailer, TwilioAPI, Knex, PostgreSQL, Kotlin

TECHNIQUES: Agile Methodologies, Paired Programming, Version Control, Flexbox/Grid

PROJECTS

ULTIMA UMBRELLA - CAPSTONE PROJECT - FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT

JAN. 2019

Capstone project required to complete Galvanize Web Development Immersive program. The application creates a easy to use, UX/UI interface to streamline communication between distributor and customer, automatically sending email/text communication in placing orders while also providing the distributor with their own platform to push notifications to remind the customer to place an order.

Kotlin | React-Native | | React | JavaScript | ExpressJS | NodeJS | Knex | PostgreSQL | Heroku | Firebase | HTML | CSS |

GALVANIZE UNITY - FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT

DEC. 2018

Group full stack project that creates UX/UI to better facilitate modern mobile devices in the the process of finding and adopting a pet.

Vue.js | Node.js | Express.js | Knex | PostgreSQL | NodeMailer | Heroku | Firebase | HTML | CSS

SNOWG STREETWEAR - WEB APPLICATION DESIGN

OCT. 2018

Web Development overhaul for local lifestyle brand.

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Firebase

EDUCATION

GALVANIZE, INC.

AUG. 2018 TO FEB. 2019

Web Development Immersive

6 month immersive 760+ hour Web Development course. The program focuses on building dynamic front-end and full stack web applications with the use of JavaScript, JavaScript based frameworks and library's, APIs, HTML, and CSS.

SELF-STUDY 2000 TO 2018

Web and Graphic Design

18 years of self-taught education using online resources, primarily in front end frameworks and libraries.

EXPERIENCE

STUDIO 401 SALON

WINTER PARK, CO MAR. 2017 TO CURRENT

OWNER

- Business plan drafting and execution
- Web/Identity/Graphic design and branding of Business
- Google Analytics/AdWords/Business platform deployment

FOUNDRY CINEMA AND BOWL

Fraser, Co

BAR MANAGER/HOSPITALITY

Oct. 2011 to Aug. 2018

- Managed team of 15+ employees for 4 years - Created graphic design for marketing campaigns/Google business solutions
- Conducted staff/personnel hiring and management
- Led organization and execution of all large events/parties